What's going on everyone? Welcome back to
another video with the School of Hard Knocks.
I'm James and today we're going to be
asking people all over downtown Austin what they're
investing right now. Whether it's stocks, real
estate, cryptocurrency, we're looking for a wide
array of answers and we can't wait to get this
content out. Let's go. If you were to go back to
when you were in either high school or college,
what is the best piece of advice you'd tell your
younger self? Don't believe what anybody tells you.
Figure it out for yourself. Only don't just
do it based on what you think or you wish
or what somebody tells you. There are a lot of forces
at work that don't have your best interest at
heart. Many more than when I was your age.
What do you think that's the result of? A
lot of it is algorithmic based decisions. You can't say
well if I do x I'll get y. When I was
just coming out of college, you know, you cut your hair, you
stopped smoking weed except on weekends, you bought
some decent clothes, you kissed some ass and to
one extent or another things would get better.
You'd make more money, you'd get promoted. There
used to be a concept they called the pre-pandemic.
Peter Principle, which said that everybody
is raised to their level of incompetence.
That doesn't happen now. What are
you currently investing in right now?
I'm mostly in conservative, for the most part,
high dividend stocks that will not do as well
in good times and they won't do as badly
in bad times. How can someone become financially free
in 2022? Compounding is your friend. If you're
young and it's 2022, unless you have really
unusual skills, you're not going
to become financially free in 2022.
And what industry did you
decide to pursue a career in?
I'm retired from the military and now I'm
in, you're welcome and thank you for recognizing that,
I am now in the consulting business.
What are you currently investing in right now?
Energy stocks and right now I'm just kind
of hunkered down because the market went down over
a thousand points today.
So for someone who's coming out of college,
what is your best piece of advice to
someone starting out in the real world today?
Intelligence, integrity and initiative.
Why those three in particular?
Because without those three, you're nothing.
Intelligence, you can develop. Integrity is
born within you. Character
matters. And initiative, keep trying.
Wow. What is the greatest lesson
that you've learned throughout the military?
Discipline. Self-discipline. Ourselves are
the hardest things to master.
But once you conquer that, the rest
of the world is open to you.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I work in media and advertising.
What are you doing in particular?
I work in sales at TikTok.
What are you currently investing in right now?
My dabble in crypto just a tiny bit and then just
the basics in mutual funds as well as a few other
companies.
What is the secret to sales in 2022?
Being human. If I'm going to sell you something,
I have to remember you still go home to somebody
else. Like you still have a home life. You still
maybe pick up your phone and go get a drink.
You're still going to be able to do it.
Maybe pick up your kid at 3
PM. You maybe just graduated, whatever it is.
How can someone become financially free in 2022?
I thought to myself, I needed to have a
wealth management person. I needed to max out my 401k.
I needed to do all of this stuff.
And really what boils down to being financially free,
whether you're 21 or 30, is based on
values-based spending. So you have to identify your value.
I prioritize gym, healthy eating, being
able to buy organic food and such,
whereas other people might
prioritize
being able to travel more or might
be able to do X, Y, Z.
If you were to go back to when
you were in either high school or university,
what is the best piece of
advice you'd tell your younger self?
Take it more seriously than I did.
Why?
Yeah, we just had a little fun. Didn't take it
too serious. And it took us a little longer until
we finished. But it gave me also the great
opportunity to do what I was loving to do.
You know, so I got to do it. And I'm happy to do
it. And I'm happy to do it. And I'm happy to do it.
And I'm happy to do it. And I'm happy to do it.
So I got into music. I started as a DJ, ended
up then as a professional DJs at the end of the
70s and the early of 80s, and then started
a career within the music industry with CBS Records,
Sony Music and Capitol.
What's going on? So this is going to be
day two of us going around downtown Austin, asking people
what they're investing in. We came out a couple of
days ago. City was kind of dead. We got a couple
of good answers, but we're trying to come back
out and really get some heat from people, old, young,
male, female, doesn't matter. We're just trying
to figure out what people are investing in.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Medical. I'm a surgeon.
You're a surgeon?
Yeah.
Wow. Okay. So as a surgeon, do you
think a college degree is necessary to be successful
in today's society?
No, no, no. College degrees are just, it's propaganda.
Wow. What are you currently investing in right now?
Real estate, myself, other people I trust, people you trust.
If you were to go back to when
you were in either high school or college,
what is the best piece of
advice you'd tell your younger self?
No limitations.
Mm-hmm.
We're just trying to scale.
I see you guys going far.
Y'all got a big, a big vision.
If you need any help, let me know.
Yeah.
Could we get a quick followup.
Do you think a college degree is
necessary to be successful in today's society?
Oh my gosh. You're going to
pull that one out on me, right?
I do.
Zuckerberg shows that it's not. I think that
Oprah Winfrey shows that it's not. I think Barack
Obama shows that it is. So we have to look inwardly
and really do a lot of soul searching to see what
our unique path is. For me, college was the
way. What is your best piece of advice to someone
wanting to start a business in 2022? I
was just having this conversation earlier today with
someone at the gym and I told him, follow
your heart. Think about what you love to do. That
thing that you would do for free and just ask
the simple question, how do I monetize it? That's it.
Simple. What industry did you decide to pursue
a career in? I'm in real estate development. What
are you currently investing in?
There's stocks, there's cryptocurrencies. Cryptocurrencies is
kind of the new thing. You look at stocks,
the volatility in stocks is very little compared to
cryptocurrency. Compare cryptocurrency to a young kid. It's
been around 10, 15 years. There's a lot
of energy. It moves very quickly. Stocks have
been around 100 years. What's your best advice for
anybody that's in real estate in 2022? I think
it's important to have a good start. I think it's
important to have a good start. I think it's
important to have a good start. It's a tricky
market right now. Things are happening in this
environment. I would say sit on the sidelines,
wait a little while, see how it plays out
before you jump in. Interest rates are rising. A year
ago would have been great. You don't always have
to be in the market. Sometimes the best trade or
the best deal you could make is sitting
on the sidelines until everything evens out before you
jump back in. I would say wait, wait a while,
let everything clear out and then get back into it,
see where things go.
What advice would you have for
someone pursuing a career in dentistry?
I'm afraid I'm not thrilled
about it now. Everything's becoming corporate,
like medicine sold out years ago and
now doctors work for hospitals. I just retired,
but I had a business I could sell and
it's changing. A lot of my friends and my wife's
a physician, but a lot of people in healthcare
say go through it with the military. Serve the
military, get your pension, then get your second job
as a doctor. Collect a pension for the rest
of your life.
Are you currently investing right now?
I'm done investing and I'm collecting.
What did you invest in throughout the years?
Equities and then annuities, bonds and things that pay
you every year for the rest of your life.
Do you have any advice for new investors?
I've gone through several financial
advisors that did nothing for me,
and then I found one who was very
receptive and you just got to keep looking.
You want it like this?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
In your opinion, how can
someone become financially free in 2022?
It's going to take you more than a year.
Right.
Well, just do what you're doing. Network
and ask people and all that stuff,
and it's going to get there.
What is the best piece of
advice you'd tell your younger self?
Don't go to school during the summer.
Go get different jobs about things that you
think you might be interested in so
that by the time you're out of college,
you've worked three or four different jobs.
So that's going to wrap it up for day
two. Just finished up downtown. We're going to be doing
these videos every single week.
Got to run into some old interviews today. Anthony
Gallion and Pat, it was awesome to see them.
And yeah, so thanks so much for watching the
video. Make sure to leave a like and subscribe.